Their world is closer than you think.
The Spiderwick Chronicles is a family, adventure,
fantasy film directed by Mark Waters.
Upon moving into the run-down Spiderwick Estate with their mother, twin brothers Jared and Simon Grace, along with
their sister Mallory, find themselves pulled into an alternate world full of faeries and other creatures.
Jared Grace / Simon Grace, played by Freddie Highmore.
Mallory Grace, played by Sarah Bolger.
Arthur Spiderwick, played by David Strathairn.
Helen Grace, played by Mary-Louise Parker.
Mulgarath, played by Nick Nolte.
Aunt Lucinda Spiderwick, played by Joan Plowright.
The Spiderwick Chronicles is a 2008 American fantasy film directed by Mark Waters and written by Karey
Kirkpatrick, David Berenbaum, and John Sayles, based on the book series by Tony DiTerlizzi and Holly Black.
It stars Freddie Highmore, Mary-Louise Parker and Sarah Bolger, with
Nick Nolte, Seth Rogen, and Martin Short in voice roles.
The film, set in the Spiderwick Estate in New England, follows three children who discover a field guide to fairies while
encountering various magical creatures such as goblins, ogres, brownies, boggarts, hobgoblins, trolls and many others.
The Spiderwick Chronicles was released on February 14, 2008, by Paramount
Pictures and grossed $163 million against its $90–92.5 million budget.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship, parent
child relationship, elves, fairy, twin brother.
The tone is emotional.